<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="shell_helper">
  <copyright><![CDATA[
    Copyright (C) 2018 Pier Luigi Fiorini <pierluigi.fiorini@gmail.com>

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person
    obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files
    (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction,
    including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge,
    publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software,
    and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so,
    subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the
    next paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial
    portions of the Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
    EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
    MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
    NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS
    BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN
    ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN
    CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
    SOFTWARE.
  ]]></copyright>

  <interface name="liri_shell" version="1">
    <description summary="create widgets and shell helpers">
      This interface is bound by a special client called shell helper
      that is responsible for helping the compositor draw its user interface.
      It can only be bound once and only shell helper is allowed.
    </description>

    <request name="set_grab_surface">
      <description summary="set grab surface">
        The surface set by this request will receive a fake
        pointer.enter event at position 0, 0 and is expected to
        set an appropriate cursor image every time the grab_cursor
        event is sent by the compositor.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface"/>
    </request>

    <enum name="cursor">
      <entry name="none" value="0"/>
      <entry name="resize_top" value="1"/>
      <entry name="resize_bottom" value="2"/>
      <entry name="arrow" value="3"/>
      <entry name="resize_left" value="4"/>
      <entry name="resize_top_left" value="5"/>
      <entry name="resize_bottom_left" value="6"/>
      <entry name="move" value="7"/>
      <entry name="resize_right" value="8"/>
      <entry name="resize_top_right" value="9"/>
      <entry name="resize_bottom_right" value="10"/>
      <entry name="busy" value="11"/>
    </enum>

    <event name="grab_cursor">
      <description summary="tell client what cursor to show during a grab">
        This event will be sent immediately before a fake enter event on the
        grab surface.
      </description>
      <arg name="cursor" type="uint"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
